Dhaka, Bangladesh alienpapon009@gmail.com (880) 1625 - 997661

# Rathijit Paul

linkedin.com/in/rathijitpapon009/ github.com/rathijitpapon www.rathijitpaul.com

I'm a software developer with 1 year of experience. I'm passionate about solving problems, writing efficient codes & developing software tools that will increase people's productivity. Currently, I'm a senior undergraduate student with a Computer Science & Engineering background.

### **Work Experience**

Junior Software Engineer Development team Free Pixel Games Ltd.
Dhaka, Bangladesh

Feb 2021 - Present

- Reduced Analytical Decision Making Time by developing various game data analytics tools.
- Improved Game Tools' Performance by implementing efficient algorithms and techniques.
- Improved Revenue Generation by continuously giving analytical reports based on user data.
- Developed web apps for showing games' ads to users worldwide.
- Developed many other internal tools, APIs & modules for the company.

Software Engineer Intern

Development team

Mainframe Labs Ltd.
Dhaka, Bangladesh

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Modularized Complex System by developing user microservice that serves user functionalities to the whole system.
- Reduced Processing Time by developing an OMR scanning tool that calculates MCQ results from formatted scripts.
- Contributed to a website's frontend collaborating with the design team.
- Learned lots of new technologies, industry-standard good practices & team collaborations in software development.

#### **Education and Certifications**

B.Sc. Computer Science & Engineering, Bangladesh University of Engineering & Technology

2017 - Present

## **Technologies and Languages**

• Languages: Javascript, Python, C++, Java, MySQL, MongoDB

• Technologies: React.Js, Node.Js, Angular, Git, Docker

• Skills: Data Structures & Algorithms, Web Development, Problem Solving, Competitive Programming

## **Projects**

Line Of Action:

React.Js | Javascript | Minimax

Developed a web-based game called the line of action. It's a part of my academic project which intends to implement Al-based games using some heuristic algorithms. See the source codes of Github.

Tour Pedia:

React.Js | Node.Js | REST API | MongoDB | Docker

Developed a full-stack web application called the Tour Pedia whose intention is to gather all the travel agencies in one place to create & host their events, make it easier for users to get an idea of travel planning, visiting places, categories, and popular food items of certain places. See all the source codes on Github.

Travel Talk:

React.Js | Node.Js | REST API | MongoDB | Websocket

Developed a full-stack web application called the Travel Talk which intends to make a social platform for travelers worldwide. See the source codes of Frontend & Backend.